It sank... at that speed?
The speed is...
No, the pressure is so intense.
And that's strike three!
He takes down Seidou's top three batters in an incredible start!
He has yet to allow a run at Koushien Stadium!
A strong hit between shortstop and third!
After giving up two runs in the first,
Seidou's ace Furuya Satoru has been showing real tenacity.
But two runs...
Those will be hard to get back.
Have you ever seen a white ball flying across the snow?
Have you ever seen a demon of a man who has sold his soul to baseball?
We didn't come from Hokkaido to enjoy baseball.
We came to take the championship banner.
And that's what we'll do!
Strike three! You're out!
As if you big-city pansies could ever stop us.
Hongou is on a roll today.
His splitters are too sharp!
Now it's time for the cleanup hitter Miyuki's third at-bat!
Pick your pitch!
You're there representing Tokyo. Start playing like it!
Miyuki connects!
Yeah!
Yes, our first hit!
That's our captain!
We won't let it end this way.
Our ace is pitching just as well as you.
Can they make use of this opportunity?
You can do it, Shirasu!
You're on target!
Yeah!
It fell off the table!
He goes down swinging!
Komadai's Hongou again leaves Seidou scoreless!
We're just getting started!
Hold them off and go again in the next inning!
It's the fourth game of the spring invitational quarterfinals.
The score has remained 0-2 since the first inning.
In the bottom of the seventh,
Komadai Fujimaki is now up to bat.
This is our inning!
Masamune!
Get us another run!
Keep it going, Furuya!
Focus on the first batter!
Up at bat is their ace, Hongou Masamune!
He has a sharp swing.
Make sure to keep it low.
Swing and a miss on an outside pitch!
No more runs.
Bring it.
Not a single one.
You won't even reach base!
Bring it, punk!
And it's caught!
Right to the left fielder!
This round of the ace battle goes to Furuya!
Those two are crazy!
They're on fire!
I don't want this game to end!
Two in a row!
That's his tenth strikeout!
Whoa! I wanna hit that!
What kind of game is this?!
They're too good!
With his form improving,
he's had perfect fifth, sixth, and seventh innings!
Looking at this, it's hard to tell who's winning the game.
That pitcher's good.
Nice pitch, Furuya!
Nice pitching!
Masamune.
You're the relief pitcher tomorrow.
Start warming up in the bullpen during the first inning.
Getting all worked up about
facing the bottom of the order.
Idiot.
Your prospects look grim.
Yeah!
Masamune, let's go!
Batting first in the top of the eighth for Seidou High School is the third baseman, Kanemaru.
Two innings left.
How will they knock him out of the game?
It's the ninth day of the spring invitational!
There are two innings left in the fourth quarterfinal game.
Will Seidou High School be able to catch up?
We...
We have to do something to support Furuya!
He pops it up!
The second baseman Nishi makes the catch for one out.
Replacing the eighth batter, Yamaguchi, is Maezono.
Now batting, Maezono.
A pinch hitter.
He can launch one into the stands.
They're hoping he can give them a breakthrough.
They just haven't been able to get a run.
Yeah!
Will the pinch hitter, Maezono, be able to get his team going?
Bring it!
Go!
It goes straight to the left fielder!
The pinch hitter flies out to left field, and Seidou now has two outs!
We're not done yet!
Hit, Asou!
You're just warming up!
The nine-hole, Asou, is up to bat.
Can he set things up for the top of the order?
I'm not going to go down easy!
He goes down swinging!
Komadai's ace, Hongou, has been pitching stupendously!
He's only allowed one hit this entire game!
Incredible!
Is he going into an even higher gear?
Once again, Hongou gives Seidou High School a zero on the scoreboard!
Nice pitch, Masamune!
You're doing great!
Nice pitching, Masamune!
You're the best!
Seidou High School is unable to
mount a comeback against Hongou!
Only one inning left to score.
If we don't catch up in the ninth,
there won't be any more pitching.
I want to stand on that mound right now!
Tomorrow, for sure...
I want to help the team with my pitching!
Can you do it?
Please let me pitch.
We're nearing the end of the quarterfinal between Seidou and Komadai Fujimaki.
After giving up two runs,
Seidou will be looking to hold Komadai scoreless as they head into the ninth starting at the top of their order.
There he is again.
I guess they can't swap him out.
They have no reason to swap him out.
Taking the mound in the bottom of the
eighth to great fanfare is Furuya Satoru!
Furuya!
You're just as good as him!
We still have the ninth inning.
Furuya is pitching so well.
We won't let this end yet.
Number 9's up next!
Start with the first batter!
Make sure to get him out, Furuya!
Everyone in the field, help him out!
Yeah, we know!
We've got this.
That guy...
This is it, guys!
We're in the lead, but we've been routed the whole second half of the game!
Let's get another run and put them down for good!
Yeah!
Let's go, Sasaki! Sock it to ‘em!
He's thrown over 120 pitches,
but Furuya keeps improving in response to Hongou.
Furuya,
just how far...
will you go?
There it is!
His fastest pitch of the day, 154 km/h!
That's what I like to see!
Incredible!
Wow.
Oh man.
Strike!
Strike three!
The last pitch was a slider!
So you've got some good breaking balls too!
Did you see how far it broke?!
Was that a slider?
How many strikeouts was that?
Eleven!
He's looking better than ever!
Nice pitch, Furuya!
Strike three!
You're out!
Another strikeout!
That's twelve!
Who is this guy?!
He really is a monster!
Furuya!
He's going toe-to-toe with Hongou!
I bet you could throw 160 km/h!
Furuya!
I'm tired.
You don't see games this good every day.
I want to hit.
I want to play.
That was unbelievable, huh?
We won't let this end yet.
I'll make sure...
Miyuki gets a chance to bat.
Both Hongou and Furuya pitched complete games,
and the only runs were the two in the first inning.
Seidou only had the one hit from Miyuki,
but Komadai Fujimaki was also outmatched by Furuya in the second half of the game.
If it wasn't for those two runs,
the outcome may've been different.
Both teams used pitcher relays to get to the quarters,
and then let their ace play the whole game.
That was the quality of the pitching in this game.
You got us good.
We couldn't even touch the ball in the last inning.
But our ace isn't bad, right?
He's way better than not bad.
He just needs to improve his attitude.
I can tell.
Don't go losing to anyone else until we meet again.
Yeah, and we'll kick your butts next time too.
Hey, Masamune.
He's trying to shake hands.
Sorry.
You beat us!
Congratulations!
Good luck!
Hey, Sawamura!
Furuya!
That was some great pitching!
Make sure you come back again!
Koushien Stadium will be waiting!
Furuya!
They let you take some of the dirt home, right?
I guess.
But not many people do it in the spring.
There's still the summer.
If you took it now, it's like you wouldn't be coming back.
Still want some?
Eijun...
Sawamura?
I need to do something.
Where are you going?
If you're gonna take some, take it from near the dugout!
There was no room for me in that game.
Damn it.
So much for "tomorrow."
No matter how much you reflect,
no matter how much you prepare,
if you don't perform when you need to,
you won't get any chances.
All you can do is watch from here.
Dirt from the bullpen?
I won't forget how much this hurt...
because I want to stand on that mound again!
Facing the towering wall before him
and seeing and experiencing his situation
all served to strengthen his resolve.
He clasped a handful of dirt on this, the day it began.
Give the stadium your respect!
Thank you!
"The Day It Began."
Those who shone at Koushien Stadium and those who didn't both want to return.
I think they feel it strongly.
What changes will the new first-years bring?
Hey, hurry up!
We need to do it before he comes!
I've waited so long for this day!
I wonder what new challenges these guys will bring.
Next time on Ace of the Diamond act II:
"Joining."
Let's win the national title!